Maud Wood Park Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Maud Wood Park Papers 1844-1979 (bulk 1886-1951)
MSS58784
Park, Maud Wood, 1871-1955
3,700 items
19 containers
7.6 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Suffragist, social worker, reformer, and author. Family papers, correspondence, subject files, speeches and writings, an autograph collection, and miscellaneous papers relating primarily to Park's activities on behalf of women's suffrage and her associations with the National American Woman Suffrage Association and the National League of Women Voters.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Alcott, Louisa May, 1832-1888--Autographs.; Allen, Florence Ellinwood, 1884-1966--Correspondence.; Barron, Jennie L. (Jennie Loitman), 1891-1969--Correspondence.; Barton, Clara, 1821-1912--Autographs.; Biscoe, Helen, 1860-1946--Correspondence.; Blackwell, Alice Stone, 1857-1950--Correspondence.; Brandeis, Louis Dembitz, 1856-1941--Autographs.; Bryant, William Cullen, 1794-1878--Autographs.; Catt, Carrie Chapman, 1859-1947--Correspondence.; Douglass, Frederick, 1818-1895--Autographs.; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963--Autographs.; Garrison, William Lloyd, 1805-1879--Autographs.; Gillmore, Inez Haynes, 1873-1970--Correspondence.; Hunter family.; Hunter, Robert Freeman, -1928--Correspondence.; Jordan, W. K. (Wilbur Kitchener), 1902- --Correspondence.; Page, Mary H. (Mary Hutcheson), 1860-1940--Correspondence.; Park, Charles Edward, -1904--Correspondence.; Park, Maud Wood, 1871-1955.; Peck, Mary Gray, 1867?-1957--Correspondence.; Rankin, Jeannette, 1880-1973--Autographs.; Shaw, Pauline A. (Pauline Agassiz), 1841-1917--Correspondence.; Sherwin, Belle, 1868-1955--Correspondence.; Stantial, Edna Lamprey--Correspondence.; Stowe, Harriet Beecher, 1811-1896--Autographs.; Washington, Booker T., 1856-1915--Autographs.; Webster, Ann--Correspondence.; Willard, Mabel Caldwell--Correspondence.; Wood family.; Wood, James R. (James Rodney). James R. Wood Civil War memoirs.
Organizations
Arthur and Elizabeth Schlesinger Library on the History of Women in America.; Boston Equal Suffrage Association for Good Government.; League of Women Voters (U.S.); League of Women Voters of Boston.; Library of Congress.; National American Woman Suffrage Association.; Radcliffe College. Women's Archives.
Subjects
Reformers.; Women--History--Sources.; Women--Suffrage.; Women--United States.
Places
United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States--Social conditions.
Occupations
Authors.; Reformers.; Social workers.; Suffragists.
Provenance
The papers of Maud Wood Park, suffragist, social worker, reformer, and author, were given to the Library of Congress by Edna L. Stantial in 1979.
Transfers
Items have been transferred from the Manuscript Division to other custodial divisions of the Library. Photographs have been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division. Books have been transferred to the general collections of the Library. One map has been transferred to the Geography and Map Division. All transfers are identified in these divisions as part of the Maud Wood Papers.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Maud Wood Park are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1871, Jan. 25. Born, Boston, Mass.
1887 Graduated, St. Agnes School, Albany, N.Y.
1889 1891 Teacher, public schools of Bedford, Mass.
1897 Married Charles Edward Park (died 1904)
1898 A.B., Radcliffe College, Cambridge, Mass.
1900 Cofounder and president, Massachusetts branch, College Equal Suffrage League
1901 1905 Secretary, Boston Equal Suffrage Association, Boston, Mass
1907 Worked and lived in settlement quarters in California, Colorado, and Washington state
1908 Married (secretly) Robert Freeman Hunter (died 1928)
1908 1910 World tour to study conditions of women around the world
1917 1920 Chairman, Congressional Committee, National American Woman Suffrage Association
1920 1924 First president, National League of Women Voters
1920 Formed the Women’s Joint Congressional Committee
1923 Headed United States delegation, Congress of the International Woman Suffrage Alliance, Rome, Italy
1925 1928 Counselor on legislation, National League of Women Voters
1928 Vice chairman, Women’s Committee for Hoover
1930 1940 Wrote several novels and plays under the pseudonym C. J. Maywood
1938 Published Lucy Stone. Boston: Walter H. Baker Co.
1955, May 9 Died, Melrose, Mass.
1960 Posthumous publication of Front Door Lobby. Boston: Beacon Press. Edited by Edna Lamprey Stantial
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Maud Wood Park (1871-1955) detail the personal life and civic involvement of a prominent feminist and social reformer who became the first president of the National League of Women Voters. Spanning the years 1844-1979, the papers are concentrated in the period between 1886 and 1951. The early material is essentially that of Park’s father, James R. Wood, Sr. Posthumous papers contributed to the collection by Edna Lamprey Stantial in the form of correspondence, notes, and miscellany relate to such figures of the suffrage movement as Florence Ellinwood Allen, Jennie L. Barron, and Carrie Chapman Catt. The collection is organized into five series: Family Papers, Correspondence, Subject File, Speeches and Writings, and Miscellany.
The bulk of the family material consists of correspondence between Park and her second husband, Robert Freeman Hunter. The exchanges begin in 1886, twenty-two years prior to their marriage, and extend to Hunter’s death in 1928. Park’s role as a leading organizer in the suffrage movement required extensive travel throughout the country, and Hunter’s career in the theater made him equally nomadic. Students of women’s history will find this correspondence particularly useful, for it contains remarks by Park on tactics, strategy, and the ideology of reform. Furthermore, the differences as well as the distances that separated Park and Hunter lend a special character to these exchanges as sources for exploring the evolution of the women’s movement. The correspondence with her husband was particularly important to Park. She considered publishing it, and much of the material is represented only in the form of transcripts. For a quarter century following Hunter’s death, she continued to write him anniversary letters on the occasion of their marriage, birthdays, and New Year’s day.
Other family correspondence supplements these themes in helpful ways, such as a revealing analysis of Park’s personality in the Hunter file that he prepared for a mutual friend, Helen Maria Biscoe. The Family Papers also include Park’s correspondence with her first husband, Charles Edward Park; the Civil War memoirs of her father, James R. Wood, Sr., a Union scout during the war; and miscellaneous Hunter and Wood family material.
The Correspondence file, particularly the special correspondence with such individuals as Florence Ellinwood Allen, Helen Maria Biscoe, Alice Stone Blackwell, Carrie Chapman Catt, Inez Haynes Gillmore, Mary H. Page, Mary Gray Peck, Pauline A. Shaw, Belle Sherwin, Ann Webster, and Mabel Caldwell Willard, documents personal friendships between Park and many of the women involved in the suffrage movement. Many of these correspondents are also represented in the Subject File because of their contributions to the various organizations and events of the period. Included also in the Subject File is information relating to Park’s lecture tours for the Boston Equal Suffrage Association for Good Government (Boston League of Women Voters), as well as papers and material relating to the activities of the Congressional Committee of the National American Woman Suffrage Association and legislative activities of the National League of Women Voters, 1922-1925.
The preservation of the papers of the woman’s suffrage movement was very important to Maud Park, and she devoted considerable energy during her retirement to securing the documentary legacy of the suffrage movement and creating conditions to sustain scholarship. Radcliffe College was at the center of her efforts and the papers illuminate her contributions to the development of the Woman’s Rights Collection and her work in establishing a series of fellowships to permit younger scholars to study there. In addition, there are materials on the development of manuscript holdings in woman’s history at the Library of Congress and elsewhere. Of special importance is her correspondence with W. K. Jordan and Edna Lamprey Stantial, as well as Stantial’s correspondence relating to the presentation of records and papers.
After retiring from an active role on the national level with the National League of Women Voters, Maud Park returned to Maine and wrote several plays and novels. Only a small representation of her literary work is present in this collection. Typescripts of the unpublished novel “Lisa” and the published play Play Stone, with correspondence, publicity folio, and some technical information relating to the production of the play by the Federal Theater Project in 1939, are a part of the writings file.
Edna Stantial indicates in her notes accompanying the collection that for a number of years Park carefully reviewed her personal papers, because her ultimate plans were to write an autobiography. Her efforts toward this goal are autobiographical notes that cover the various phases of her life from pre-school days to approximately 1946.
The Park papers conclude with an autograph collection containing letters and autographs of many prominent political, social, and literary figures of the nineteenth and twentieth centuries, including Louisa May Alcott, Clara Barton, Louis Dembitz Brandeis, William Cullen Bryant, Frederick Douglass, Robert Frost, William Lloyd Garrison, Jeannette Rankin, Harriet Beecher Stowe, and Booker T. Washington.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged in five series:
Family Papers, 1864-1952
Correspondence, 1894-1953
Subject File, 1845-1976
Speeches and Writings, 1896-1947
Miscellany, 1844-1979
Container List
- Family Papers, 1864-1952 (Box 1-4)
  Correspondence between Park and second husband, Robert Freeman Hunter, as well as other members of the Wood and Hunter families. Miscellaneous writings, personal papers, and clippings concerning family members.
  Material arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent and chronologically within, followed by separate files for general correspondence and other material of Robert Hunter, James Wood, Sr., and James Wood, Jr.
  - Correspondence with Robert Freeman Hunter (second husband) (Box 1)
    - 1886-1916, (7 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1916-1952, undated, (5 folders) (Box 2)
  - Correspondence with Charles Edward Park (first husband), 1902-1903 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence with Wood family (Box 2)
    - Wood, George E., 1910-1913 (Box 2)
    - Wood, James R., Sr., 1907-1911 (Box 2)
    - Wood, James R., Sr., 1911, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Correspondence with Hunter family (Box 2)
  - Hunter, Robert Freeman (Box 2)
    - Correspondence with Hunter family, 1926-1928 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence with Helen Maria Biscoe (Box 2)
    - Correspondence with Mary H. Page, 1918-1924 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence with Mabel Caldwell Willard (Box 3)
    - Business correspondence, 1910-1927 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence concerning convalescence of, 1927 (Box 3)
    - Condolences on death of, 1928 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous personal papers (Box 3)
    - Miscellany, poems, 1897-1928, undated (Box 3)
    - Miscellany, writings, 1915 (Box 3)
  - Wood, James Rodney, Sr. (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1884-1910 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence concerning, 1909-1914 (Box 3)
    - Clippings, 1904-1914, undated (Box 3)
    - Notes, “Civil War memoirs” (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous personal papers, 1864, 1872 and 1913 (Box 3)
    - Writings, “Civil War memoirs”, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous writings (Box 4)
    - Miscellany (Box 4)
  - Wood, James Rodney, Jr. (Box 4)
    - Business correspondence, 1909-1936 (Box 4)
    - Clippings, 1932-1943 (Box 4)
- Correspondence, 1894-1953 (Box 4-5)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent to friends and colleagues.
  Special correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and chronologically within each file, followed by alphabetically arranged general correspondence.
  - Special, 1894-1950 (Box 4)
    - Allen, Florence Ellinwood, 1912-1948 (Box 4)
    - Biscoe, Helen Maria, 1912-1929 (Box 4)
    - Blackwell, Alice Stone, 1916-1950 (Box 4)
    - Catt, Carrie Chapman, 1918-1929, 1940-1944 (Box 4)
    - Coolidge, Calvin, 1925 (Box 4)
    - Griffin, B. H., 1894 (Box 4)
    - Hay, Mary Garrett, 1918-1924 (Box 4)
    - Edwards, Marie Stuart, 1946, undated (Box 4)
    - Gillmore, Inez Haynes See same container, Irwin, Inez Haynes (Box 4)
    - Irwin, Inez Haynes, 1933-1947 (Box 4)
    - James, Harlean, 1941-1946 (Box 4)
    - McCormick, Cyrus H., undated (Box 4)
    - Meredith, Ellis, 1941-1947, undated (Box 4)
    - Morgan, Mary, 1928-1940, undated (Box 4)
    - Paige, Mabeth H., 1940-1947, undated (Box 4)
    - Page, Mary H., 1901-1943 (Box 5)
    - Peck, Mary Gray, 1933-1950 (Box 5)
    - Priest, Alice L., 1938-1940 (Box 5)
    - Robbins, Mary C., 1940-1944 (Box 5)
    - Russak, J. Ben, 1939-1946 (Box 5)
    - Shaw, Pauline A., 1908-1914 (Box 5)
    - Sherwin, Belle, 1941-1946 (Box 5)
    - Smith, Rena B., 1925, 1944-1945 (Box 5)
    - Webster, Ann, 1925-1947 (Box 5)
    - Willard, Mabel Caldwell, 1918-1940 (Box 5)
  - General (Box 5)
    - A-J, 1905-1946, undated (Box 5)
    - K-Z, 1894-1953 (Box 5)
- Subject File, 1845-1976 (Box 5-13)
  Correspondence, memoranda, newspaper clippings, notes, printed materials, and reports.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Air raid warden, 1942 (Box 5)
  - Barron, Jennie Loitman (Box 5)
    - Correspondence with Edna Lamprey Stantial, 1953-1959 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence concerning, 1957-1960 (Box 6)
    - Clippings, 1958-1959 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous printed matter (Box 6)
  - Birth control referendum campaign, 1943 (Box 6)
  - Biscoe, Helen Maria (Box 6)
  - Blackwell, Alice Stone (Box 6)
    - Alice Stone Blackwell Fund (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
      - Blackwell family, 1907-1942 (Box 6)
      - Davis, Malcolm B., 1942-1946 (Box 6)
      - Stantial, Edna Lamprey, 1931-1943, undated (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous, 1898-1945 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence concerning estate of, 1950-1951, 1957 (Box 6)
    - Memorabilia (Box 6)
    - Notes to Edna Lamprey Stantial (Box 6)
    - Notes, miscellaneous, and printed matter (Box 6)
  - Blackwell, Antoinette Brown (Box 7)
    - Biographical notes (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and clippings, 1909-1975 (Box 7)
  - Blackwell, Elizabeth (Box 7)
    - Family correspondence, 1845-1893 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and printed matter, 1847-1877, 1914, 1949, undated (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence concerning books and papers of, 1959-1966 (Box 7)
  - Blackwell, Lucy Stone (Box 7)
    - Correspondence (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1847, 1885 (Box 7)
    - Miscellany (Box 7)
  - Boston Equal Suffrage Association for Good Government, Boston, Mass., miscellaneous correspondence and reports, 1901-1909 (Box 7)
  - Boston League of Women Voters, Boston, Mass. (Box 7)
    - Lecture series (Box 7)
      - Abstracts of, circa 1920-1921 (Box 7)
      - Clippings, 1919-1920, undated (Box 7)
      - Contracts, 1919-1921 (Box 7)
      - Correspondence, 1919-1921 (Box 7)
  - Cable Act, 1922 (Box 7)
  - Catt, Carrie Chapman (Box 7)
    - Correspondence with the New York Public Library, New York, N.Y., 1921-1925 (Box 7)
    - Condolences on death of, 1947 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence concerning books and papers of, 1947-1950 (Box 8)
    - Miscellany (Box 8)
  - Christian Science Monitor, 1947-1948 (Box 8)
  - Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies Congress of the International Woman Suffrage Alliance, Rome, 1923 (Box 8)
  - Council of American Soviet Friendship, 1944-1948 (Box 8)
  - Cumberland County League of Women Voters, Cumberland County, Maine, miscellaneous correspondence and clippings, 1944-1946 (Box 8)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 8)
  - European tour, notes, 1929-1930 (Box 8)
  - Gardener, Helen H. (Box 8)
  - Get-Out-the-Vote Campaign, 1944 (Box 8)
  - Harper and Brothers, 1925-1927 (Box 8)
  - Hoover, Herbert (Box 8)
    - Women’s National Committee for Hoover (Box 8)
      - Correspondence, 1928-1932 (Box 8)
      - Speeches by Park (Box 8)
      - Miscellany (Box 8)
  - Massachusetts Woman Suffrage Association (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1915-1919 (Box 8)
    - Narramore case (Box 8)
  - National American Woman Suffrage Association (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1917-1919 (Box 8)
    - Congressional activities, 1918-1919 (Box 9)
    - Congressional Committee reports, 1917-1919 (Box 9)
    - Financial records, headquarters, 1916-1919 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous clippings and printed matter (Box 9)
  - National College Equal Suffrage League, 1908, 1912 (Box 9)
  - National Committee for Medical Rights in Massachusetts (Box 9)
  - National Committee to Abolish the Poll Tax, 1944-1947 (Box 9)
  - National Committee for Medical Rights in Massachusetts (Box 9)
  - National Committee to Defeat the Unequal Rights Amendment (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1939-1946 (Box 9)
    - Printed matter, 1943-1946, undated (Box 9)
  - National Council of Women, 1932-1940 (Box 9)
  - National League of Women Voters (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1920-1944 (Box 9)
    - Legislative activities, 1922-1925, 1943, undated (Box 9)
    - Pamphlets and printed matter, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Proceedings, 5th Annual Convention, 1924 (Box 10)
    - Programs, convention, 1921, 1924, and 1938 (Box 10)
    - Publicity releases, 1920-1924, undated (Box 10)
    - Speaking schedules, Maud Wood Park, 1920 (Box 10)
    - Miscellany (Box 10)
  - National Woman’s Party (Box 10)
  - New England Woman Suffrage Association, minutes, May 28, 1900 (Box 10)
  - Non-Partisan Campaign to Defeat Senator John W. Weeks, 1917-1918 (Box 10)
  - Pan-American Conference of Women, 1922 (Box 10)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 11)
  - Radcliffe College, Cambridge, Mass. (Box 11)
    - Schlesinger Library, annual reports, 1951-1960, 1964-1978 (Box 11)
    - Woman’s Rights Collection (Box 11)
      - Clippings, 1943 (Box 11)
      - Correspondence (Box 11)
        - Comstock, Ada L., 1943 (Box 11)
        - Park, Maud Wood, 1942-1946 (Box 11)
        - Stantial, Edna Lamprey, 1942-1978 (Box 11)
      - Guide, 1943 (Box 11)
      - Indices to Maud Wood Park Papers, circa 1943 (Box 11)
      - Invitations and miscellaneous printed matter (Box 11)
      - Lists of sponsors, 1943 (Box 12)
      - Organizational plans (Box 12)
      - Women listed in, 1943 (Box 12)
      - Robinson-Shattuck papers (Box 12)
      - Miscellany (Box 12)
  - Shaw, Pauline A. (Box 12)
  - Sheppard-Towner bill, 1921, 1927-1928 (Box 12)
  - Stantial, Edna Lamprey (Box 12)
    - Correspondence (Box 12)
      - Allen, Florence Ellinwood, 1960-1962 (Box 12)
      - Suffrage Archives Committee, 1957-1967, 1976 (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous, 1927-1962 (Box 12)
    - Ford Foundation, 1960 (Box 12)
    - Front Door Lobby, correspondence and clipping notebook, 1958-1961 (Box 12)
    - Notes (Box 12)
  - United States Department of Labor (Box 13)
    - Children’s Bureau (Box 13)
    - Women’s Bureau (Box 13)
  - United States House of Representatives (Box 13)
    - Hale, Robert, 1943-1947 (Box 13)
    - Keating, Edward, 1918 (Box 13)
    - Woodhouse, Chase Going, 1945 (Box 13)
  - United States Senate (Box 13)
    - Brewster, Owen, 1941-1946 (Box 13)
    - Lundeen, Ernest, 1940 (Box 13)
    - Sheppard, Morris, 1940 (Box 13)
    - White, Wallace H., Jr., 1940-1945 (Box 13)
  - Who’s Who publications, 1940-1943 (Box 13)
  - Woman’s Centennial Congress (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 13)
    - Miscellany (Box 13)
  - Women’s Action Committee for Victory and Lasting Peace (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 13)
    - Miscellany (Box 13)
  - Women’s Joint Congressional Committee, 1923, 1927 (Box 13)
  - Work Projects Administration, Federal Theater Project, 1939 (Box 13)
  - World tour (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, 1909-1910 (Box 13)
    - Letters of introduction, 1909-1910 (Box 13)
    - Notes (Box 13)
    - Miscellany (Box 13)
- Speeches and Writings, 1896-1947 (Box 13-16)
  Handwritten and typewritten drafts, copies of speeches, writings, and plays, notes, correspondence relating to plays and novels written by Park, miscellaneous poems written by Park, and writings of others.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Speeches (Box 13)
    - 1907-1924, undated (Box 13)
    - 1926, undated (Box 14)
  - Writings (Box 14)
    - “Some Famous Boston Churches,” Woburn Journal, 1894 (Box 14)
    - “Travels of Anna and Me,” Saturday Evening Gazette (Boston), July-Oct. 1898 (Box 14)
    - “Clothes and a Cause” (Box 14)
    - “Lisa”, (5 folders) (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1935-1937 (Box 14)
    - “Remember the Ladies” (Box 15)
    - “Victory: How Women Won It,” notes, 1922 (Box 15)
    - “Women, Their Rights and Nothing Less” (Box 15)
  - Plays (Box 15)
    - “It Could Happen in Washington,” 1936 (Box 15)
    - Lucy Stone (Box 15)
      - Typescript, (2 folders) (Box 15)
      - Correspondence with producers, 1938-1939 (Box 15)
      - Correspondence with publishers, 1937-1941 (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1937-1940 (Box 15)
      - Clippings, 1938-1939 28 (Box 15)
      - Press/publicity folio, 1939 (Box 16)
      - Miscellany (Box 16)
    - “Opponents in American Revolution” (Box 16)
    - “Your Street and Mine” (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 16)
  - Poems, 1896-1947, undated (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous writings by others, 1899-1927 (Box 16)
- Miscellany, 1844-1979 (Box 16-19)
  Autobiographical notes, biographical notes, clippings, printed matter, legal documents, pamphlets, miscellaneous fragments and autograph collection.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material with autograph materials filed at the end.
  - Autobiographical notes (Box 16)
    - Compilation by Park, (3 folders) (Box 16)
    - Editorial notes, 1954-1979 (Box 17)
    - Notes to editor, 1934 (Box 17)
  - Biographical data (Box 17)
  - Clippings (Box 17)
    - 1864-1919 (Box 17)
    - 1921-1927 (Box 17)
    - 1932-1948 (Box 17)
    - 1961-1979 (Box 17)
  - Greeting cards received (Box 17)
  - Invitations and postcards (Box 17)
  - Legal documents, including birth, copyright, and marriage certificates; grade school material; and college diplomas (Box 17)
  - Memorabilia, (2 folders) (Box 17)
  - Notes, class (Box 18)
    - circa 1895-1896 (Box 18)
    - 1898 (Box 18)
  - Organization solicitations (Box 18)
  - Pamphlets (Box 18)
  - Printed matter (Box 18)
  - Resolutions, 1919, undated (Box 18)
  - Travel documents, passports (Box 18)
  - United States Senate and House joint resolutions, bills, proceedings on woman suffrage, 1900-1921 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous unidentified typescripts (fragments) (Box 19)
  - Autograph collections, 1844-1946, (3 folders) (Box 19)